hello
it is uh April 5th
and we're in our second discussion of
chapter five in cohort three
so this is going to be our final
recorded session for the first half of
the textbook chapters one through five
and then
next week we'll have an unrecorded
session we will have time to to fill out
the feedback form for those who haven't
yet
we'll discuss project ideas which people
can also add ideas to we'll just talk a
little bit more broadly and informally
about the textbook and about the
textbook group
and then we will have a
inter-semester break or it's not a
semester but uh uh intermission
and we'll pick up when cohort 4 begins
we'll pick up with a second half
of cohort 3 going through just as
previous cohorts did
chapter 6 7 8 9 10 and so on so
we're in our second discussion of
chapter five
I'll head over there now and we'll begin
just with anybody in the chat or via
raising their hand or just unmuting
how does chapter five
sit with you
what are any
thoughts or questions about
chapter five that you want to just raise
at the outset
Jonathan
yeah I sort of feel that um while in
some sense it says that you don't need
to have digested chapter four to
understand chapter five it still feels
like you know there's a lot of
background there which which is really
important and the the lack of technical
Clarity for from chapter four I sort of
feel there's a bit of a hangover
um from that into chapter five
the technical debt hangover
yes
okay
thank you Maria
I was a bit frustrated with this chapter
because I thought it would be more
insightful but it seemed to me it was
just more the same bunch of equations
narrated and plotted
yes
I guess the um the apologists view would
be chapter four was equations and plots
in general
and chapter five in contrast is applying
it to the specific mammalian nervous
system examples
and to empirical studies
however broadly I totally agree with
that
any any other just
thoughts or primary Reflections on
chapter five any aspect of it or some
part of the discussion or even any other
active inference learnings over the last
week or two
that
come to your attention when you're in
this setting
foreign
right in the chat Terry you wrote I was
struck by the similarity to neural
networks
you could describe a little more if you
want to unmute or
we can see how that might come into play
in the previous chapter 10 discussion
from cohort three we were playing with
the idea of of
reading chapter 10 first
to provide a lot of the conceptual scope
and the historical connections and
similarities and dissimilarities of
active inference with other topics
and so like it's interesting to note
neural network
is is described in the citations and
twice in chapter 10 in this paragraph
but there's a lot of context
that is kind of held out
till
chapter 10.
but the intuitions that you're having
along the way are
um very good
any other just general thought or a
question on five
otherwise we will look to the questions
and
um address those which we haven't
addressed previously
and then
continue on through
okay
so continue on this neural network just
while we're
here
let's use the figure
5.5
so here we have 5.5 up
the cortical
system
the
limbic or the midbrain system
associated with policy selection
and
the spinal
motor execution Arc using this
differential between
perceptions and set points
and so then
Terry you wrote
the series of nodes passing information
along a chain with inhibitory mechanisms
alongside
yet neural networks use Transformers
while active inference uses free energy
well
great topic
to go deeper into the relationship
between neural networks
and free energy principle and active
inference models
in live stream 51
I'm just going to the slides now
the core claim
is that here on the right we see the
Markov blanket and the internal and the
external States
sense coming in perception
action selection resulting in embodied
action
and uh
an effect upon the generative process
the niche which then provides
observations
so this is how we've been looking at it
in
the textbook
on the left side we see in a three-layer
neural network
an input layer
one or more
compute or intermediate layers which can
have a wide range of connectivities
and then some output layer so this could
be the image comes in and the classifier
label comes out or the classifier label
comes in and the image generated comes
out
and then it
acts in an environment which then
provides another observation
and in this paper
they demonstrate that the variational
free energy
on this partition
is equivalent to the loss function on
this neural network
so the training of this neural network
is monotonically related to the
variational free energy loss on this
model learning
the loss function is the function that's
being minimized to update this neural
network and so it's really quite a
stunning conclusion
because the topologies so how the pieces
are connected of these two models
is entirely different
so in live stream 51 there's more detail
on that
um
neural networks use Transformers while
active inference uses free energy and
Jonathan as Transformers in the
post-2017 technical sense
so in the sort of attention is all you
need
pre-trained Transformer
timeline that we're on
that's a good question and that feels
specifically like a reinforcement
learning framework or is it more General
so I I meant there in terms of the the
diagram you were giving where there was
some neural network and a sort of
feedback on an environment
um yeah this this one here which yeah it
looks like a sort of RL
um framework but are you saying this is
sort of more more General than that
foreign
it is more General As I understood the
paper
describing that for the observation
sequence one to T
and the parameterization all the weights
of the neural network
and then analogously the variational
free energy of those very same
observations and the parameterization of
the base graph
these two are monotonically related
within a certain
classes
quite broad classes
yes it was I I mean it's
I believe a very major
recent finding
because it suggests that we can have
this like this on one hand it looks like
a circuit board and it's it's a lot to
look at
however
there is a semantic interpretability
here we see prior
hidden State B that's how things change
Through Time hidden State changing
Through Time hidden state so there's
hidden States changing Through Time
here's the a matrix emitting
observations or you could recognize
observations
decision making preferences guiding
decision making so it's like there is an
interpretability to this base graph
and so the idea that a neural network
which can have an arbitrary topology
with absolutely no semantic
interpretability
kind of like any given neuron
in a real neural system
I mean Jennifer Aniston neuron aside no
neuron plays an explicit semantic role
let alone a one-to-one semantic role
so the idea that this kind of a
aggregate
system
would have a representation where the
variables are semantic
is quite a claim and then the notion
that the training function for both of
them are monotonically related is really
important
not to go too far afield from the
textbook but just neural networks are
bought in and that's an example of some
very recent research that makes that
connection go beyond intuition
okay here's a question that I don't
think that we addressed previously but
if anyone else has any other question
please raise your hand or write in the
chat
so table 5.1
gives a remarkable association between
neurotransmitters and precisions should
we be suspicious that this seems so
clean or is this evidence that the
framework is a good match for real brain
functioning
what what does anyone think or
what was their prior suspicion before
seeing the table
and then what was their posterior
suspicion after they saw the table
Jonathan and then anyone else
yeah so this this was my question I I
think I was just surprised that there
was sort of this apparent one-to-one
correspondent or at least near
one-to-one correspondence so I think I
would have expected in a different
neurotransmitters to have you know
a more
um I guess just they're not to be this
this very clean relationship
um that was my prior
foreign
ly these molecules
do
um things
that are not only listed here like
serotonin the word means blood pressure
serotonin was discovered in the blood as
was dopamine
and it has a variety of effects on
immune cells
and then later was understood to play a
role in the central nervous system so
I don't think that these evidence
provided
are suggesting that the exclusive
function
of these neurotransmitter type molecules
is
um that they're exclusively
and exhaustively described by these
evidences
however these do provide empirical
patterns
of everything from histology
to um
association with cognitive functions
neuroimaging studies
um gene expression analysis
pharmacological manipulation like the
whole molecular Neuroscience toolkit
these are quite disparate
phenomena
and their disparate phenomena that on
one hand have been linked
mechanistically to a given molecule
and Associated receptors in all of this
but on the other hand these phenomena
are conceptually linked
to certain to the semantics of certain
parameters in these statistical models
so
maps are not territories it's not saying
that it's exhaustively described
however
if we use this Association as a
heuristic if not a hypothesis
and we find that we have unique
explanatory and predictive powers
then
by the standards of science
it was a valid modeling
approach
these are explanations
and predictions
that would not be achievable
without mapping
a molecule to the semantics of a
parameter
like just searching acetylcholine on a
literature search engine
you'll find a whole variety of different
studies different study types different
outcomes different species and so on
so that's the um scruffy
the scruffy is what the search engine
just gives you
each paper is unique every experiment is
unique
and then the the the neater the neat
would be like all neurotransmitters do
one thing
and so somewhere that is
useful enough to help us make
explanations and predictions
but not so terminally differentiated
that we can't link together novel
strands of evidence into explanations
and predictions
somewhere
bridging or respecting the neat and
Scruffy
articulation is active inference
and the ways that we can use statistical
models
to connect to these broad empirical
results
on different chemicals
so
should we be suspicious that it's so
clean well yes they're presenting their
arguments
like a prosecutor
they're not necessarily going into every
caveat or bringing up studies that might
um disconfirm that
so for sure it's connecting dots and not
all the dots are being shown and not all
the connections are being shown
but it moves the discussion forward
about how aspects of maps
which are to say cognitive models
are related to aspects of territory
which include the actual
materiality of the neural system
Michael and then anyone else
hello Daniel
um sorry I've been
um out of pocket for a week or so but um
I'm trying to catch up in the way I'm
trying to make sense of what I'm uh now
Landing into I wanted to kind of
validate does this make sense or not
make sense
um if if one were to think and the way
I've been trying to the mental models
that have been trying to map this
conversation into are about social
conversations and when you could say one
level of activity up from if you will
the biological biochemistry and I was
thinking if these were
uh verbs you know sorry if each of these
um neurotransmitters were nouns verbs
adjectives and that sentences were being
created you know they could be created
many different ways but but that there
are units of
of composition if you will of of message
signaling that are are creating
um
larger sentences in in in at that level
of the system would that metaphor make
sense or would it be missing
um how might it be a mismatch for what
has happened
great question
does anyone have a thought on that
potentially referencing figure 5.5 or
any other area
but any thought on this question
oh I'll give a first thought then please
anyone can build on it so
um
what is speech really it's this
continuous flow of like phonemes and and
so it is not subject object verb
in how it actually is like the
materiality of speech is vibration in
the air and all of that in the
embodiment and so that's like the
territory of speech but let's just say
that we're putting on our linguist hat
so now we're going to think about
certain parts of speech as like subject
object verb or noun an adverb and so on
even though the speaker may have not
thought about it that way
so
we're making maps of sentences as
linguists
even if the speaker didn't use that map
when they generated the speech
let's think about what sentence
does this whole figure represent
um
and uh beliefs about this and beliefs
about that
lead to some differential contrasts
in light of incoming evidence
and the result of that
is
now we're going to leave that little
clause
and the result of that contrast in light
of incoming evidence is
a decision-making process about what to
do
given Precision on the decision-making
process
and one of the outcomes
of that decision-making process
is
a descending prediction
that contrasts with incoming sensory
data and results in an action
hopefully it's not too mixed of a
metaphor
but absolutely
these different compositions
just like infinite grammar you can keep
on adding yes and also in the social
space
you can keep on adding sentences to each
other and make longer paragraphs you can
keep on making longer sentences or lists
similarly you can keep on making larger
generative models
or different generative models
and so
different connections amongst these
units
are going to be described kind of like
by the genre
like that was a haiku
that was a sentence with no noun
that was a question that was a directive
so loosely
it's a great
working model
to think about this as a graphically
arranged sentence
that's expressing something
where some of the nodes
some of the tokens
are associated with more belief like
States
some of the nodes are associated with
observations
capacities for action and so on
and so we can kind of like play with
Legos play with language
and compose like well what if there were
these three sensory modalities and two
action possibilities and decision making
was done this way
that's a generative model
cool yeah and and then
and then however that sentence is
diagrammed
it simply wouldn't be the actual speech
itself
it wouldn't be the vibration of the the
voice box or the air
so that's like map territory
but once we're in the map
then sentences might have this kind of
structure
or this could be the dependency
of an organization
or the dependency structure of claims
in a scientific Corpus
that's kind of what Bayes graphs do
they describe different variables and
their associations
and that also speaks to their
flexibility
like you could know all of these and
solve for that one
or you could just have these ones and
try to reduce your uncertainty about
those
that'd be like a sentence where
um
you did hear the first part but not the
second part or vice versa
thank you Dan again every time I join
these conversations my mind gets mental
models get blown open and thank you
again
good well hopefully they're not
um
reduced to Rubble because your your
intuition was was
um right
about taking a linguistic approach I
mean who's to say it's right
it certainly is compatible
and um these this is like a composition
um this is a setting where we can
compose generative models
and so that's why sometimes it's like a
little challenge like what's the active
inference um answer on attention what's
the answer on memory it's like those are
complex cognitive phenomena that play
out differently in different systems
so if the framework were
rigid enough to give an answer to that
in general it wouldn't have the latitude
that we need
to actually describe that phenomena
and so we want to have the latitude to
describe different phenomena including
unnamed phenomena
in systems we haven't seen yet
which means that the framework itself
can't be so specific about how certain
things play out
it's mind-blowing it's absolutely
mind-blowing
um
and it's such a problem I know I said
every time it's such a privilege to be
in this conversation and witnessing you
make sense of it through this complex
Collective lens when I've been thinking
in blocks and um and these blocks are
being you know it's like no these aren't
bricks they're flows and and it works
cause and effect works differently and
it's just as I say mind-blowing and uh
and daunting but thank you
thank you it's definitely a team efforts
and we've been through it many times in
many people's insights have been folded
together
um
does anyone else in chat or raising
their hand want to
have any reflection on five or a
question or we can
um
look over some sections and then in the
in the last minutes we can like look
ahead to the second part of the book
or or whatever people prefer
is there a nerve a neural system
or some embodied
behaviors that people want to
investigate
I'll add in this
question
okay thank you Jana are there better or
sorry are there alternative
visualizations that better show the
interdependencies
that's really
interesting question
um
in a base graph
the edges reflect
um
yeah and I'll add this in thank you in
the base graph the edges reflect
a certain kind of statistical connection
amongst variables
but
this entire structure
it's kind of like
[Music]
um
a web
or like a tensegrity sculpture
or like a guitar string
um in that
the really an edge like let's just say
it from this S3 to Pi 3.
but yes but then if policy selection
ends up doing something in the real
world then that is going to influence
future proprioceptive inputs
so
even edges that aren't shown
it's not that they're not associated
with each other
through the reality of the system
but the edges are showing the kind of
direct connections again not the
anatomical direct connections
then it would just be an anatomy
textbook
but it's showing the direct
informational or causal connections
um
so how can we visualize the
interdependencies
there's so many
ways you might explore but I really like
that as something for us to think more
about like one more traditional way
in terms of scientific visualization
would be we could plot
um S3 as a on the x-axis and
um you know mu sub x one on the y-axis
and then we could ask whether there was
any correlation or Mutual information
between those two variables
so the fact that they're not connected
it doesn't mean it's going to be just a
blur
in fact they might be very strongly
associated with each other
but through
um some intermediate notes
so that would be one way of looking at
whether to Any Given nodes two or three
or however many whether they have
associations and or interdependencies
um and then I guess another like little
layer is like the space of the counter
factual
like some interdependencies might not be
revealed unless something changes in the
system
so that is also a layer where
um
two things might have no correlation and
then you remove
um
you remove an edge and then all of a
sudden two things that weren't in
association
um now are
um okay I I I don't think that's a
complete answer because there's a lot of
work with visualization to be done but
that is just kind of some aspect of it
um
but then just continuing with the honest
question that then to Jonathan so so it
is like a magnetic coil
the electric field is not going along
the coil it is a field
a lot to think about don't
have a specific thought if anybody wants
to add something but yes I
like what if these are wires and then
there's like fields of influence that
aren't just the wires but the
connections are are there and they're
relevant but then there might be
other dependencies that aren't simply
mapped out on The Wire dependencies
um
okay Jonathan I'm going to copy your
question in
has this been looked at in hypograph
language rather than graphs
um
in active block fronts
we we looked briefly at hypergraphs
we haven't seen any active hypographs
but
it's very interesting
a graph Through Time
so for example what if um this right now
there's a static topology
so even if there's Dynamic information
flowing through this graph you could say
that it's a static graph
the referent is dynamic it's changing
through time but the structure is not
changing Through Time
but what if um on even and odd time
steps
um this connection existed or not
then that kind of a of a system
as far as I understand is um
a hypergraph
is there some other aspect to hypergraph
Jonathan or what would enabling this
inactive inference help us do
so hypographs sort of allow for more
General types of edges
um it it sort of allows for edges which
specifically go through vertices kind of
the the easiest um example is a is a
plain routing system airplanes where if
a single airplane goes from
um airport A to B to C
um it's very clear that it's the same
airplane that's gone between those and
just by drawing an edge between A and B
and B and C that doesn't give the same
information that sort of a single piece
of information or a singular single
airplane has taken a particular route so
it just allows for for more
generalizations of
um of edges than in in a regular graph
I just wonder essentially about the the
way you can encode the types of
information that move through a
um through a regular graph and a
hypograph and one might be able to
encode more specific information in a in
a hypograph
yeah very interesting I'm pretty sure
that it hasn't been
written on in active a lot of the papers
seem very recent like the one you point
to is um 2018
and the others are recent so it's um
it'd be an interesting area
um one note on this to kind of um
speak to the other side where the kind
of map
uh is very effective with respect to the
territory for better and For Worse
what if these were computers and these
were the literal wires connecting them
in that case
you could design in silico
or cyber physical systems
where the edges of the base graph
very well mapped to the causal structure
of the system
physically
so
the the kind of
one of the hardest systems
and one of the richest systems is like
trying to make simple statistical models
of the brain but when making just in
silico systems
so just simple pedagogical models or
intuition pumps
or in certain systems for for um digital
and Communications systems
the edges can have a much more
um
clear interpretation
because as laid out in the beginning of
five
this is kind of
this is the tension and the dream
would be what what if the actual
anatomical
connections
amongst these cell types
what if those were actually reflective
of the structure of a base graph
and and you'll note that they're not
exactly exactly the same
like just here's you know two to three
and here we see that's two to three but
also it goes from here from
from um four to two but we don't see a
four to two in the tissue
so but but it's close enough but clearly
not close enough to Merit calling this
simply layer 5.
and then I guess to the electric field
these connections are the neural
connections
what if there are glial connections what
if there are electric fields
um influences
like what the EEG measures
um
are some of the electrical phenomena
of
these cells
and actually just a specific kind of
electrical phenomena of these cells the
EEG outside of the head
but those electrical signals are not
only
um outputs
like Epi phenomenal to neural activity
they're also inducing different changes
in neural activity as well
so that there's also physical edges that
aren't shown just you know complex
systems are complex
and they engage in in multiple
mechanistic ways
which is why it's important to have maps
of them Ali
uh yeah uh well actually going back to
Yana's question and also to uh touch on
what Jonathan just uh mentioned uh well
uh in fact when we're talking about uh
interaction uh obviously there are many
different conceptions of this term
interaction so we can talk about
physical interaction which is basically
uh I mean for the most part
um is undertaken uh the fields so we can
also term it as a kind of field
interaction but there are some other
conceptions of interaction
actually there are many others but
probably one of uh the most important
conceptions for our purposes is
information theoretic interaction uh so
uh when we're talking uh talking about
message passing or uh this conception of
interaction through and I mean
information passing or information
theoretic conception of it we're not
necessarily
deciding on what's it what exactly is
the medium of interaction or
transmission because it can be uh
abstracted away this medium of
transmission or interaction and we can
just look at the
um I mean mathematical framework of
um or the mathematical structure of
those information so for instance
um say uh IIT framework integrated
information framework in which uh well
in information
integrated information Theory
it's unable to distinguish a highly
interdependent set of components
dominated by a redundant relations from
an equally
strongly interacting set of combo
components exhibiting a kind of strong
Synergy between them so this is actually
kind of a limitation for IIT for some
people because
since redundancy indicates that
although a strong interaction is needed
to ensure that a component is a kind of
repetition of the other components it
does not imply that the set of
components support Collective emergent
Behavior which is entirely different
from that of the individual components
so in recent years by recent I mean
since 2020 there are some interesting
Works in that regard trying to formulate
uh the the interdependencies and
emergence with mathematical formalism so
Lionel Barnett if I remember his name
correctly and also Anil Seth and others
for custom of their names has done some
pretty interesting work in that regard
in recent years and one of the uh
interesting things they've came across
is that they've tried to apply this uh
abstract conception of interaction and
interdependencies from information
theoretical theoretic point of view to
neuroimaging datas and uh so they
and they've been able to
describe this interaction of neural
interaction between different brain
regions without accounting
explicitly accounting for synaptic or I
don't know a junction uh interaction or
so on so it's much more abstract and
much more generalized form of uh
interaction
awesome
yes
anatomy and physiology are different
Anatomy is describing
the articulations of the system
but then the physiological relationships
and correlations and even causes
are not necessarily
following along the anatomical lines
and
um
if one wants the anatomical answer
you can just slice the tissue and take
the picture
so something different is happening with
this modeling
and it's important like you mentioned
that this interaction concept amongst
variables
by the time we're labeling variables
we're in the map
we're not labeling the tissue anymore
so the only possible kind of interaction
that these variables can have is like
statistical or information theoretic
but then there's this tantalizing
dream
slash fallacy slash actionable framework
all of those
that parameters do map onto aspects of
the territory and that's the map
territory
dialectic
some maps useful in some contexts
doesn't reify the the architecture of
the map
and it doesn't prove or disprove any
architecture of the system
and the interesting thing is that's not
even active inference specific
these are active inference type thank
you Ali
these are active inference or predictive
processing like models
however
any statistical or cognitive modeling
approach is going to confront this issue
and then how do we move Beyond just
simply saying well map territory means
we we can't drive or we can't do route
planning
it's like well if dopamine is associated
with Precision in this model
where should the deep brain stimulator
go or what kind of food would make sense
to eat or not eat
or and so on so we can actually reduce
uncertainty about what actions to take
using Maps
and that's what these are
and those Maps
arguably
works best when
it's understood what's a map and what's
the territory
and understanding what the map is can be
fully described
and held to the standards of of
reproducibility
whereas holding a territory to those
same epistemic Norms or criteria
it it doesn't even make sense
the territory can't be fully described
but when they're overlaid
even symbolically
it can become
ambiguous
well
next week we're going to
um
not record
so if you're going to be there again
that's awesome
otherwise please fill out the feedback
form in the future textbook group
section and check out the project ideas
but in these last 10 minutes today
is there any sections or questions on
chapter five
that anybody wants to look at or
would
people like to see into chapter six
um I've just added those additional
comments I was making into
your coda
and I'm making a quick visualization
of what I was thinking about I'm not
sure if this relates directly to the
model
um but just I'll need a minute to
get this done thank you all I'll leave
the tab up we'll return to it
any preference for a section of five or
to to look ahead to chapter six in the
recipe
even though we'll return to that in like
a month
well
looking at yes go ahead Michael
I was going to say no objection here I
just wanted somebody to respond okay
let's revisit the whole first half of
the book which you all have now
completed one or more passes through
chapter one provided an overview
chapters 2 and 3 describe the low road
and the high road the low road how are
we going to do it with Bayesian
statistics uncontentious
why
at the very least we need repeated
measurement if something can't be
repeatedly measured by us
it's not a thing to us
and then a little bit more from the
inside if something can't take adaptive
action or more adaptive action to
persist and repeatedly measure itself
it won't be that kind of thing either so
whether you view
from the outside repeated measurement or
you view from the inside adaptive action
we can model both of those in terms of
this self-evidising
primary imperative
how are we going to model that
self-evidising primary imperative
Bayesian statistics
chapter four
with all of its
shakes and bumps
was describing the generative models of
active inference and how variational
Bayesian inference is used
as a heuristic or an approximation
to otherwise intractable Bayesian
statistical models and we just looked at
chapter five
which characterized a few subsystems of
the mammalian neuroanatomy
and then linked them together and
provided some references to other models
that go into a lot more detail
computationally and and molecularly
here's what is going to be coming up in
the second half of the book
that is the application oriented part of
the book now it may not go all the way
to the guidebook Playbook handbook that
we all expect and prefer but it is more
pragmatically an application oriented
than the first half of the book
in chapter 6 there's a recipe for
Designing active inference models with
some here we've even gone through that
recipe but broadly they're going to lay
out some steps
about systems of interest about
specification of the generative model
and the generative process and there's a
lot of good discussions around even
broader considerations like why are we
making this model who are we making the
model for is this model being used
descriptively
like historically or is it being used
proactively
that's the recipe so you want to open up
a restaurant
here's the active inference recipe
chapter 7 and chapter 8
are like a pair
chapter 7 is going to cover
generative models that have discrete
time characteristics chapter 8 is going
to look at octave inference in
continuous time
discrete time active inference on the
top of figure 4.3
continuous time active inference
generative model on the bottom of figure
4.3
so chapters 7 and 8 are going to
basically zoom in on figure 4.3 in
sequence
chapter 9 model based data analysis is
going to describe some of the framings
and challenges and opportunities
associated with
integrating empirical data
with these kinds of generative models
so far up till then it's kind of been
like here's the generative model we
constructed and now we're going to
simulate Its Behavior
so generative model specification
simulation in silico generation of
synthetic data
but we're not always just interested in
generating synthetic data sometimes we
want to take in empirical data from
measurements and that's what this
chapter is about
and then chapter 10 is a longer chapter
there's no equations or figures
and it is a Capstone that's describing a
lot of the conceptual and historical
context and as kind of referenced
earlier
um may make sense to even read first
that is where we're going in the second
half of the cohort so the first half as
the authors lay out is epistemic we're
getting like the roads into the city
what the city is about or one restaurant
in the city
and then a few dishes that have been
prepared in this city
then we're going to go behind the scenes
look at the recipe for Designing those
models
talk about two subtypes of Cuisine the
discrete time and the continuous time
talk about connecting these generative
models to measurements
so that people can do analyzes and write
papers and all of that make things that
do things in the world
and then having done all of that chapter
connects a lot of dots
that's the par at all textbook and for
being here you all are at least half
done with it
and um
as also mentioned we we go at a similar
pace
we haven't set the dates yet for the
second half of cohort three
it'll likely pick up again in May when
we have cohort 4 begin with chapter one
and um if you have any feedback or ideas
it would be extremely appreciated
to fill out this feedback form just
directly in Coda you can just submit it
right there
as well as to share the link for others
to join and convey to them just say hey
stick around you will learn it's not XYZ
or it is XYZ
but feel free to share that so that we
can have really engaged and awesome
cohorts such as this one and also any
other comments you want to write there
or any thoughts on how we can improve it
and next week
um we're gonna Focus all about that
we're gonna
not record that session
we're going to talk about the project
ideas table
overall Reflections on the first half
next steps in about the future of the
textbook group
um
[Music]
Jana I'll look forward to your image and
in the last minute or two anyone else
please feel free to add other comments
it's not exactly goodbye as we will meet
again but this is the last recording
for this half of the cohort
I'll uh put the image in Coda
um in a few minutes so I'll I'll let you
know Discord uh when it's ready thank
you and it just makes me think about
like these base graphs are kind of like
the statistic this is the necessary and
sufficient information for a statistical
model
but
we might tell stories or link
associations that don't follow this
exact topology
so this is not like the only web we can
draw but it's a really important one
for certain kinds of statistical models
all right
so next week same time
for
um
feedback
and next steps
thank you everybody see you then